# Chitrang Patel

265 Yorkland Blvd, North York, ON M2J 1S5 | +1 (437) 922-8906 chitrang200889@gmail.com | https://chitrang200889.github.io/vcard/

### **Present**

Pursuing post-graduation in Mobile Application Design and Development Co-op program from Lambton College(3.95 GPA) in Toronto campus. Ready to apply my 4 years of experience in Android and following technologies that I will learn during course work.

- Swift, iOS
- Java, Android
- Cross-Platform and mobile browser apps
- Game and Wearable app development

#### **Technical Skills**

- Design Pattern MVP
- Reactive Extension RxAndroid
- Networking Retrofit, OkHttp3, Volley
- Data Parsing JSON, XML, SOAP
- Data storage SQLite, Content Providers, Shared Preferences, External Storage
- Version Control GitHub, Bitbucket, GitLab, SVN

## **Employment**

## Sr. Android Developer(Tech Lead)

Nov 2016 - Nov 2017

BosLeo Pvt. Ltd.

Valsad, India

- Requirement analysis and project documentation
- Translated business requirements into working solutions
- Approached and implemented new technology to maximize product efficiency

## Sr. Android Developer(Team Lead)

Sep 2015 - Oct 2016

**Dynamic Dreamz Websolutions** 

Surat, India

- Communicated with client, technical and management team and end users to collect requirements, described software product and its feature and technical details
- Mentored co-workers by reviewing and improving code
- Provided suggestions and feedback to designing team to enrich user experience

### **Android Developer**

Jun 2013 - Aug 2015

Krtya Softwares

Surat, India

- Designed, developed and deployed mobile applications successfully on play store
- Created mock-ups, wire-frames and working prototypes for client-related projects
- Learned development tools android studio, eclipse and android simulators

#### Education

Post Graduate - Mobile App Design and Development Lambton College	Present - Sep 2019 Toronto, Canada
Master of Engineering - Computer Science Indian Institute of Science	2012 Bangalore, India
	0040

Bachelor of Engineering - Information Technology

2010

LDCE, Gujarat University

Ahmedabad, India